Guide to the Benét Family Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Starr Nelson Gift, 1942-1950; 1.04; 3 boxes
  The correspondence between the two appears to start with a short autograph letter from Benét (1886-1950) to Nelson (1910-?), dated August 12, 1942, in which Benét informs Nelson that he is accepting her poem, "The Lovers in Ascension," for publication in the Saturday Review.
  - Correspondence
    - Volume I, 1942–1944 (Box 15, Folder 199-200)
      Includes copies of poems and photographs
    - Volume II, 1944–1945 (Box 15, Folder 201-202)
    - Volume III, 1945–1946 (Box 15, Folder 203-204)
    - Volume IV, 1947 (Box 16, Folder 205-206)
    - Volume V, 1948–1949 (Box 16, Folder 207-208)
    - Volume VI, 1949–1950 (Box 16, Folder 209-210)
  - Other Material
    - Scrapbook, 1947-1950, undated (Box 17, Folder 211)
    - Material removed from scrapbook, 1950, undated (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 279)
- Material from Other Sources, 1912-1979; 1.04; 3 boxes
  Acquired by gift and purchase, 1941-1979.
  Material from Other Sources contains other small gifts and purchases of material relating to the Benét family. Correspondence is subdivided for Stephen Vincent and William Rose Benét correspondence and consists chiefly of outgoing letters. The largest files can be found for correspondence between Stephen Vincent Benét and the publisher Doubleday and Company, and for correspondence between William Rose Benét and the poet Jeremy Ingalls and the Saturday Review. The Saturday Review file contains original letters to Benét and other staff members at the journal, original letters from Benét to other staff, and carbons of outgoing letters. A good amount of Saturday Review correspondence is with translator Rae Dalven.
  Writings feature multiple works, inclduing drafts and printed versions, by Stephen Vincent Benét. Other noteworky writings include a draft, typescript and autogarph manuscript, of an autobiography by James Walker Benét (1857-1928) and a setting copy, corrected and with printer's annotations, of Muriel Rukeyser's Theory of Flight (Yale University Press, 1935). Rukeyser's collection was awarded the Yale Younger Poets Prize in 1934. Stephen Vincent Benét, who served as editor of the series from 1933 to 1942, made the selection and wrote a foreward to the 1935 publication.
  - Correspondence
    - Stephen Vincent Benét Correspondence
      - Allan, [Ralph D.], undated (Box 18, Folder 212)
      - Babb, James T. (James Tinkham), undated (Box 18, Folder 213)
      - Belitt, [Ben?], undated (Box 18, Folder 213a)
      - Bradley, Mrs. Franklin T., 1939 February 27 (Box 18, Folder 213b)
      - Carter, John Franklin, undated (Box 18, Folder 214)
      - Crawford, Jack Randall, 1934, undated (Box 18, Folder 215)
      - Davidson, [Eugene], [1935 July 14?] (Box 18, Folder 215a)
      - Doubleday, Doran & Company, 1927–1942 (Box 18, Folder 216-217)
      - Hart, M. M., undated (Box 18, Folder 218)
      - Jackson, Stuart W. (Stuart Wells), 1940 February 11 (Box 18, Folder 219)
      - Knollenberg, Bernard, undated (Box 18, Folder 220)
      - Morison, Samuel Eliot (transcription), undated (Box 18, Folder 221)
      - Price, Allan, 1942, undated (Box 18, Folder 222)
      - Samson, H., undated (Box 18, Folder 223)
      - Shaw, Thomas S., [1933?] September 6 (Box 18, Folder 224)
      - Stephens, Pauline Frances, 1933–1934 (Box 18, Folder 225)
      - Taylor, William, undated (Box 18, Folder 226)
      - Tuttle, H. E. (Henry Emerson) (transcription), undated (Box 18, Folder 227)
      - Ware, [John N.], undated (Box 18, Folder 228)
      - Wing, Donald Goddard, 1942 January 25 (Box 18, Folder 229)
      - Yale University Press, [1928?]-1935 (Box 18, Folder 230)
      - Unidentified, undated (Box 18, Folder 231)
    - William Rose Benét Correspondence
      - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1931 (Box 18, Folder 232)
      - Bacon, Leonard, 1913 December 2 (Box 18, Folder 233)
      - Cady, Harrison, 1943-1950, undated (Box 18, Folder 234)
      - Clipping removed from Cady, Harrison, 1950 April 23 (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 280)
      - Cushing, John P., 1922 December 24 (Box 18, Folder 235)
      - Davidman, Joy, 1949 (Box 18, Folder 236)
      - Fisher, A. Hugh (Alfred Hugh), 1912–1926 (Box 18, Folder 237)
        Includes photographs
      - Fletcher, John Gould (photostats), undated (Box 18, Folder 238)
      - Ingalls, Jeremy, 1942-1950, undated (Box 18, Folder 239-240)
      - Envelope removed from Ingalls, Jeremy, 1951 January 8 (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 281)
      - Jackson, Stuart W. (Stuart Wells), 1946 September 8 (Box 18, Folder 241)
      - Johnson, Robert Underwood, [1913 May 28] (Box 18, Folder 242)
      - Lindsay, Vachel, 1913–1932 (Box 18, Folder 243)
      - Loveman, Amy, 1935-1950, undated (Box 18, Folder 244)
      - Nettleton, [George Henry], 1943 April 20 (Box 18, Folder 245)
        Includes clipping
      - Clipping removed from Nettleton, [George Henry], 1943 March 14 (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 282)
      - Saturday Review of Literature, 1946–1948 (Box 18, Folder 246-247)
      - Saturday Review of Literature, 1948-1950, undated (Box 19, Folder 248-249)
      - Sinclair, Upton (photocopies), undated (Box 19, Folder 250)
      - Stephens, Pauline Frances, 1934-1937, undated (Box 19, Folder 251)
      - Taggard, Genevieve (photostats), undated (Box 19, Folder 252-253)
      - Taylor, Prentiss, 1944 September 12 (Box 19, Folder 254)
      - Williams, Esther, 1949-1950 (Box 19, Folder 254a)
  - Writings
    - Benét, James Walker
      - [Autobiography], draft, typescript and autograph manuscript, undated (Box 19, Folder 255)
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent
      - "Abraham Lincoln," screenplay, typescript mimeograph, circa 1930 (Box 19, Folder 255a)
        Written with Gerrut Lloyd
      - "The Captive," story, typescript, corrected, with proofreaders' marks and printer's annotations, undated (Box 19, Folder 256)
      - "Five Sketches," galley proof, signed, undated (Box 19, Folder 257)
      - " The General's Lady by Esther Forbes," review, typescript carbon, corrected, circa 1939 (Box 19, Folder 258)
      - "Good Wine," review of The Wind Bloweth by Donn Byrne, printed version, The Literary Review, 1922 October 28 (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 283)
      - "The Headless Horseman," musical score, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 284)
        Written with Douglas Moore
      - "Hymn of a Reader to the New York City Librarians," poem, printed version, The Villager, 1952 April 10 (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 285)
      - "Listen to the People," printed version, 1941 (Box 19, Folder 259)
      - "Songs of Dear Old Yale," poems, typescript carbon, corrected, and autograph manuscript, undated (Box 19, Folder 260)
      - Envelope removed from "Songs of Dear Old Yale", undated (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 286)
      - "Story Idea," draft, typescript, undated (Box 19, Folder 261)
      - "We, the members of the Wolf's Head Society..." printed version, [1942] (Box 19, Folder 262)
      - Untitled, undated (Box 19, Folder 263)
    - Benét, William Rose
      - "My Brother Steve," essay, printed version, 1943 (Box 19, Folder 264)
    - Bennett, Ethel Harper
      - "Epic Qualities," thesis, typescript carbon, undated (Box 19, Folder 265)
    - Hackett, Helen
      - "It Happened at the Brick Row," essay, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 19, Folder 266)
    - Rukeyser, Muriel
      - "Theory of Flight," setting copy, corrected, with printer's annotations, circa 1935 (Box 20, Folder 267)
  - Other Material
    - Clippings, 1941, undated (Box 20, Folder 268)
    - Clipping, 1977 April 23 (Box 21 (Oversize), Folder 287)
    - Drawing by William Rose Benét, 1938 (Box 20, Folder 269)
    - "Fourth Floor Funnygraph," typescript and typescript carbon, 1915–1916 (Box 20, Folder 270)
    - Printed material, 1933-1953, undated (Box 20, Folder 271)
    - Publicity, 1968, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 272)
- Restricted Fragile Papers, 0.21; 1 box
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 22: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 2, folder 19 (Box 22, Folder 288)
  - Box 2, folder 22 (Box 22, Folder 289)